Roo Williams

150 Dekalb Ave Ground Floor Brooklyn 11217

347-322-8679 roo@roowilliams.com roowilliams.com @roowilliams

Profile

Fueled by a burning curiosity and desire to make tomorrow better than today, I strive to create products and experiences that leverage the possibilities unlocked by a networked world.

I am an Interaction Designer and strategic business thinker with a passion for making products and experiences at the intersection of our physical and digital worlds. T-shaped person with a broad range of skills from strategy to production, technical to creative, I am solutions-oriented in any context. A naturally curious mind that is able to harness creative energy. An innate ability to deliver laser focused, succinct insights plus the vision and skills to execute great work at any level of fidelity. Able to generate clear vision for teams and confident enough to lead from the bottom up.

Experience

Senior Creative Technologist - Anomaly, New York City

09/2015 - 09/2017

Anomaly is a marketing agency that understands that everything is media, and so specializes in addressing client challenges more broadly as a business issue, analyzing and offering creative solutions in everything from design to product development.

Anomaly was AdAge's 2017 Agency of the Year

- → Championing advertising that is useful rather than distracting.
- → I created a collection of industry-wide projects as a way to evangelize and develop my own critique of this concept: Branded Utility
- Building prototypes to test and sell in ideas using HTML5/CSS3, full-stack
 JavaScript, Sketch, InVision, Arduino, Raspberry Pi, 3D Printing.
- → Serving as an in-house tech-lead, consulting with producers.
- → Building production level websites.
- Git version control using Github and BitBucket
- Server configuration and deployment (DigitalOcean)
- Facilitator of maker culture within the organization with initiatives like <u>Anomaly SkillShare</u> and teaching people to use digital fabrication tools.

Product Designer/Labs Tech Lead - TMW Unlimited, London 07/2012 - 07/2015

TMW Unlimited are an award-winning customer engagement agency.

→ Using emerging technologies to concept and build products that bring technical innovation to life at TMW Unlimited.

150 Dekalb Ave Ground Floor Brooklyn 11217

347-322-8679 roo@roowilliams.com roowilliams.com @roowilliams

- Managing build teams and using product design skills for physical builds.
- Project themes include connected objects, contextual/physical computing.

Graphic Designer - Brand42, London

06/2012 - 07/2012

Worked on UI design for a James Bond, Skyfall campaign for VisitBritain.

Nike iD Design Consultant - Niketown, London

11/2010 - 01/2012

Duties involve premium customer service, tailored storytelling alongside footwear customizations and telling brand stories.

Product Design Assistant - Adapt-React, Russell Square, London

07/2009 - 10/2009

Paid summer internship helping to develop various products including a notebook case, fabric vase, coat rack and indoor sundial. Duties included creating drawings for laser cutting, getting quotes from suppliers and manufacturers, product development, sketch modelling and packaging design.

Graphic Designer - CC Sports, Bargoed, South Wales

09/2005 - 08/2008

In-house graphic designer for a printwear and promotion company. Duties involved print design for team wear, design and production of promo material, sporting awards, signage and developing a web presence. Other duties involved implementation, maintenance and administration of the companies IT system.

Education

BA Product Design - Central Saint Martins, London Student representative, selected to exhibit at New Designers Showcase 2012 2009 - 2012

Foundation studies in Art and Design / **Merit** - Central Saint Martins, London 2009

Skills

Natural collaborator, get-stuck-in attitude, ability to lead or assist

Art direction and graphic design

Research and analysis methods, Jobs to Be Done

Design thinking: iterative design, human centered design

UX: personas, journeys, flows, wireframes

Communication: client presentation & pitch skills, ability to clearly discuss and explain solutions with both technical and non-technical team members

Design: concepts, grid systems, Sketch, Adobe CS

Digital prototyping: JavaScript, jQuery, Node.js, Experience with React/Vue, React Native

Physical prototyping: 3D modelling, 3D printing, laser cutting, workshop skills

Physical computing: Arduino, Raspberry Pi, Electronics